Guide to the Albert Ellis papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series II: Library and Research Files, 1931-2007
  - "Informal History of Approaches to Sexual Counseling in America and the Rational-Emotive Approach to Sexual Counseling"--Unpublished Version From Approaches to Sexual Counseling Workshop in Irvine, CA, 1974 March 22-23 (Box 55)
  - "How to Cope with a Fatal Illness," by Albert Ellis and Michael Abrams--Drafts and Notes, 1993, Undated, (6 folders)
  - Untitled, 2003, Undated, (7 folders) (Box 117)
  - Coursework (Box 115)
    - "Are Some of Your Best Friends Dangerously Disturbed?" Undated (Box 115)
    - "Article Memo The Facts of Love," Undated (Box 115)
    - "Article Memo The Ingredients of Beauty: A Scientific Analysis," Undated (Box 115)
    - "Biog," Undated (Box 115)
    - The Case of S.B.J., Undated (Box 115)
    - Case Study, Undated (Box 115)
    - "A Case Study With Multiple Symptoms," 1952 (Box 115)
    - "A Comparison of the Use of Direct and Indirect Phasing in Personality Questionnaires"--Submitted in Partial Fulfillment of the Requirements for the Degree of Doctor of Philosophy, In the Faculty of Philosophy, Columbia University, Undated (Box 40)
    - "Education 222T2, Outline of Course, 1941"--Professor Helen M. Walker, 1943 (Box 104)
    - "The Contributions of Projective Techniques in the Study of the Mentally Deficient," 1950 (Box 115)
    - "Do Personality Tests Really Measure Personality,1945 (Box 115)
    - "Essentials of a Psychological Report," Undated (Box 115)
    - "Facts of Love," Undated (Box 115)
    - "The Family as an Educational Agent," 1943 (Box 115)
    - "First Report of Group II Topic III: The American Tradition at Bay," Undated (Box 115)
    - "Fourth Group Report: Topic VI: Toward an Adequate Faith," 1943 (Box 115)
    - "Horneyism versus Science--A Special Review," 1951 (Box 115)
    - "Individual Paper: Human Nature and the Social Order," 1943 (Box 115)
    - Re: Kinsey, 1953 (Box 115)
    - L.A. Intensive Personal Data Questionnaire, 1983 (Box 115)
    - "Men Without Women," 1952 (Box 115)
    - "Old Articles," 1943-1945, 1956-1957, Undated, (2 folders) (Box 115)
    - "Preliminary Outlines for A Critical Evaluation of the Environmental and Constitutional Factors in the Etiology of Homoeroticism," 1943 May (Box 40)
    - "Projective Methods in the Study of Personality," 1946 (Box 115)
    - "Sample Case History: The Case of Miss R.," Undated (Box 115)
    - "Statutory Offense," Undated (Box 115)
    - "A Study of Projection in Personality Questionnaires," 1946, (4 folders) (Box 115)
    - "Symonds Psychology of Human Adjustments," Undated (Box 115)
    - "Term Report: Child Love," 1943 (Box 115)
    - "Term Report: Child Love," 1943 January 6 (Box 40)
    - "Test Your Marriage," Undated (Box 115)
    - "The Theory of Personality Structure and the Behavior of Human individuals," 1952, Undated, (2 folders) (Box 115)
  - Lyrics, Undated
    - "Rational Songs," "Rational Humorous Songs," Undated (Box 115)
    - "Irrational Popular Songs," Undated (Box 115)
    - Notes-Autobiography and Original Song Lyrics, 1967-1975, Undated (Box 114)
    - Rational Humorous Songs, Volume I, Undated, (2 folders) (Box 113)
    - "Songs Already Typed or Copied"--Notes and Drafts, Undated, (2 folders) (Box 89)
    - "Original Songs and Miscellaneous," Undated (Box 89)
    - "Duplicates," Undated (Box 89)
    - "Duplicates," Undated, (4 folders) (Box 111)
    - "Other Songs and Poems, I and II," 1983-2004, (3 folders) (Box 111)
    - "Miscellaneous Music," 1977 (Box 111)
    - Rhymes Without Reason, 1931-1934 (Box 80)
    - Short and Snappy, Undated (Box 80)
    - A Garland of Rational Songs (Set to Old Favorite Tunes), by Albert Ellis, Institute for Rational Living, 1976 (Box 89)
    - The New York Times Nostalgic Years in Song, Edited by Irving Brown, 1974 (Box 89)
    - Popular Songs of Nineteenth-Century America, Introduction and Commentary by Richard Jackson, 1976 (Box 89)
    - Gilbert and Sullivan: Everybody’s Favorite Series No. 6, 1938 (Box 89)
    - Stephen Foster Songbook: Original Sheet Music of 40 Songs, by Stephen Collins Foster, 1974 (Box 89)
    - Sousa’s Great Marches, Selected and Introduced by Lester S. Levy, 1975 (Box 89)
    - 100 Best Songs of the 20’s and 30’s, Introduction by Richard Rogers, 1973 (Box 89)
    - Everybody’s Favorite Songs, 1933 (Box 77)
    - John M. Williams’ Favorite Melodies For the Adult, 1935 (Box 77)
    - Richard Wolfe’s Legit Professional Fake Book More Than 1010 Songs, Undated (Box 77)
    - 1001 Jumbo Song Book, 1976 (Box 77)
  - General (Box 40)
    - "Al’s 80th Birthday Shame Attack!" by Dr. Mitchagoss, 1993 September 26 (Box 40)
    - "Al on Coaching,"--Notes, Undated (Box 113)
    - "Coaching Practicum," 2001 (Box 81)
    - Supervisory Certificate Practicum, July 15-18, 2004 Debbie Joffe, Albert Ellis Institute," 2004 (Box 104)
    - Albert Ellis Institute--Papers, Notes, Advertisements, Workshops, 2003-2004, (3 folders) (Box 104)
    - Albert Ellis Institute, 2003-2004 (Box 76)
    - "An Intelligent Person’s Guide to Contemporary Guru’s in the Western World," by Howard W. Polsky, Columbia University, Undated (Box 56)
    - American Counseling Association 1999 World Conference--Counseling in the Postmodern Era, 1999 (Box 56)
    - "At the Dawn of the Sexual Revolution: The Letters of Ira Weiss and Albert Ellis, 1956-1967"--Includes Correspondence with Ira Weiss, 2001, Undated, (4 folders) (Box 109)
    - "Declaration of Interdependence Constituting Our United States,"; "Progress Report on Interdependence," Undated (Box 115)
    - "Do It Yourself Eye Movement Technique," by Fred Friedberg, 2001, (2 folders) (Box 40)
    - Book Reviews, 2003 (Box 72)
    - Book Reviews, 1957-1991, (5 folders) (Box 101)
    - "Workshop and Seminar Materials," Undated, (3 folders) (Box 109)
    - Book and Article Titles, RET, General Psychology, Undated (Box 50)
    - Book and Article Titles, Suggested Talks and Workshops, General Psychology, Undated (Box 50)
    - Picture Vocabulary Cards and Tests, Undated (Box 50)
    - "SSM (revised)," Undated (Box 50)
    - Taming Your Inner Brat: A Guide for Managing Self-Defeating Behavior, by Pauline Wallin, Beyond Words Publishing, Inc., 2001 (Box 40)
    - Term Abbreviations, Undated (Box 50)
    - Testing, 1962-1963 (Box 50)
    - Postmodern--"Main Papers," 1968-1999, (2 folders) (Box 56)
    - Transpersonal Psychology, 1989-1995 (Box 56)
    - Forwards, Undated (Box 69)
    - "Headings for Articles," Undated, (2 folders) (Box 69)
    - Reprints
      - Book Chapters and Articles, 1972-2003, Undated, (2 folders) (Box 69)
      - Book Chapters and Articles, 2001-2003 (Box 72)
      - Book Chapters and Articles, 1992-1999, (2 folders) (Box 72)
      - Articles, 1970-1989 (Box 107)
    - "Running Head: Discussion of Padesky and Beck," 2002 (Box 69)
    - "Kluwer Academic/Human Sciences Press," 2003 (Box 69)
    - "Why I Became a Therapist," Undated (Box 69)
    - "Social Psychol," Undated (Box 69)
    - "Bridging the Divide: Linking Basic Science to Psychotherapeutic Interventions-A relational Frame Theory Account of Rational Emotive Behavior Therapy," Undated (Box 69)
    - Pamphlets, 2001-2002 (Box 69)
    - "Rational Emotive Behavior Therapy with Children, Adolescents and Families," 1999 (Box 69)
    - Irrational Beliefs (Ibs) From Albert Ellis and Robert A. Harper, A Guide to Rational Living, 1997 (Box 69)
    - Bibliography, 1945-2005, (7 folders) (Box 69)
    - Playboy Magazine Forum Responses, 1966 (Box 74)
    - Workshops Conducted by Ellis, 2002, Undated (Box 74)
    - REBT Course: Emotional Efficiency, 1997, Undated, (6 folders) (Box 74)
    - "Basic ABC Model of Rational Emotive Behavior," Undated (Box 74)
    - REBT Courses, 1973-1995 (Box 74)
    - "Interviews," 1999-2002 (Box 74)
    - "Entry in Ency of Sex," 2004 (Box 74)
    - Psychology Today, 2003-2004 (Box 74)
    - Tribute to Albert Ellis on His 75th Birthday, 1988, Undated (Box 73)
    - Ellis’s 91st and 92nd Birthdays, 2004, Undated (Box 73)
    - "Albert Ellis Live!" by Windy Dryden, Undated (Box 73)
    - "Mindfulness, Acceptance and Relationship: Expanding the Cognitive-Behavioral Tradition," by Steven C. Hayes, Victoria M. Follette and Marsha Linehan, Undated (Box 73)
    - Sex Puns, Undated (Box 84)
    - "Extra Material" With References, Undated (Box 84)
    - "Personal Papers"--Bills, Travel Documents, Registration Form for National Register of Health Service Providers in Psychology, 1997-2003 (Box 84)
    - "Notices and Attendance Certificates--Various Seminars, Conferences, Etc.," 1989-2002 (Box 84)
    - Draft Review by Shawn Blau of "Reason and Emotion in Psychotherapy" To Appear in Contemporary Psychology, Undated (Box 84)
    - Drafts and correspondence with Shawn Blau, 1997-2002, Undated (Box 84)
    - "Ellis Emotional Efficiency Inventory" By Shawn Blau and Albert Ellis--Includes Notes, Correspondence, Drafts, 1995-2002 (Box 84)
    - Table of Contents of Journal of Mental Health Counseling--Including Article by Albert Ellis, 2000 April (Box 84)
    - Document Resume for "Three Methods of REBT That Make My Psychotherapy Effective," By Albert Ellis, Undated (Box 84)
    - Mockup and Press Kit For "How to make Yourself Happy" By Albert Ellis, 1999 June (Box 84)
    - "REBT Practicum on Addiction"--Phoenix, AZ Workshop Correspondence with Emmett Velten, Notes, Drafts, 2001 (Box 84)
    - REBT Pocket Companion by Windy Dryden and Michael Neenan, Foreword by Albert Ellis--Includes Notes, Correspondence, Drafts, 2003 (Box 84)
    - Israel America Foundation--Albert Ellis Workshop, 2004 (Box 84)
    - "Albert Ellis Institute: Overview of Branding Assignment" Presentation by Real Good Idea, 2004 October 11 (Box 84)
    - Andy Hopson of Real Good Idea--Includes Correspondence and Presentation, 2004 August -October (Box 84)
    - Albert Ellis Institute--Press Kit, Staff Memoranda, 2003-2004, (3 folders) (Box 84)
    - "Remembering Paul Meehl"--Correspondence and Drafts, 2004 (Box 84)
    - Springer Publishing Co. Catalog--Includes Books by Albert Ellis, [2004] (Box 84)
    - Japanese Institute for REBT, [2002] (Box 84)
    - "At the Dawn of the Sexual Revolution"--Correspondence with Ira L. Reiss, 2001-2002 (Box 84)
    - "REBT Y2K"--Draft by Leonor Lega with Ellis Notes, Correspondence, 2000 July 29 (Box 84)
    - Ted Crawford Articles and Correspondence with Albert Ellis, 1992, 1993 (Box 84)
    - Albert Ellis Letters to the Editor Regarding Self-Esteem, 2002 (Box 84)
    - Albert Ellis Letters to the Editor, 1953-1983, Undated (Box 84)
    - Playboy Magazine Forum--Responses by Albert Ellis, 1976, 1979 (Box 84)
    - Foreword to Peiser and Sandry Book and Chapter for Zweig Book, Undated (Box 84)
    - Proposal--"A Meeting of His Holiness the Dalai Lama and Dr. Albert Ellis," 2001 (Box 84)
    - "REBT and Irrational Beliefs in the Elderly: Acknowledging One’s Mortality," Undated (Box 84)
    - "Cognitive Restructuring of Disputing of Irrational Beliefs," 2002, Undated (Box 84)
    - "Dryden," 2003 (Box 84)
    - Current Psychotherapies, 2002-2003 (Box 84)
    - Titles: Albert Ellis, Ph.D., 1992 October 21 (Box 84)
    - "Sestito Book," 2003, Undated (Box 84)
    - Published Articles, 2001, Undated (Box 84)
    - Bedwetting--Transcript, Discussion, Speech by Albert Ellis, Undated, (2 folders) (Box 78)
    - Reprints
      - Articles, 1950-1999 (Box 78)
      - Book Chapters, 1960-1967, Undated (Box 78)
      - Articles--"Intellectual Fascism", 1984-1985 (Box 78)
      - Articles--"Intimacy", 1977, Undated (Box 78)
      - Book Chapters and Articles, 1947-2003, (4 folders) (Box 78)
    - "Learning, Living, Loving"--"Talk at MAMSE Conference, Michigan," 1973 April 5 (Box 78)
    - "Kognitive Elemente in nichkognitiven Psychotherapien" (German translation of article by Albert Ellis), 1991 (Box 78)
    - "Softology," 1995 (Box 78)
    - "Elliot Cohen" of the Institute of Critical Thinking, 2001 (Box 78)
    - "APA, Hawaii," 2001 (Box 78)
    - "Ira L. Reiss," 2002-2003 (Box 78)
    - "Dryden," 2002-2003 (Box 78)
    - "Personality Disorder," 2001-2002 (Box 78)
    - "Clinical Psychology Psychotherapy," 1997-1999, (2 folders) (Box 78)
    - "Personality Theory," Undated (Box 78)
    - "Gamiel,"--Ruchama Gamiel, 1995-1998 (Box 78)
    - Proposed Review by Susan Levine of Sex Without Guilt in the 21st Century, 2004 (Box 78)
    - "To Read and Re-file," 1967-1972 (Box 107)
    - "This and That," 2000-2003 (Box 113)
    - "Questionnaires and Travel Documents," 2003-2005 (Box 113)
    - Friday Night Workshop--Volunteers and Questionnaires, 1990-2001, (2 folders) (Box 113)
    - Weekly Planners, 2001-2004, (2 folders) (Box 81)
  - Clippings--Annotated Newspapers and Articles (Box 86)
    - AIDS, 1992 (Box 86)
    - Anxiety, 1967-1979, (9 folders) (Box 106)
    - Anxiety, 1999-2002 (Box 113)
    - Biological, 1967-1977 (Box 52)
    - Cognition, 1968-1974 (Box 52)
    - Free Will, 1960-1977 (Box 52)
    - Existential, 2000-2003, (2 folders) (Box 113)
    - Fear, 1961-1963 (Box 106)
    - Health, 2002 (Box 86)
    - Illogic, 1951-2005, (13 folders) (Box 53)
    - Illogic II, IV, V, 1997-2005, (18 folders) (Box 102)
    - Illogic, 1977-2005, (2 folders) (Box 54)
    - Illogic, 1940-1973 (Box 86)
    - Index, Undated (Box 86)
    - Insomnia, 1990 (Box 86)
    - Mistakes, 1960-1979, (8 folders) (Box 54)
    - Mistakes, 1971-1991, (9 folders) (Box 96)
    - Modeling, 1969-1984, Undated (Box 54)
    - Money, 1977, 1990 (Box 54)
    - Motivation, 1971-1990 (Box 54)
    - Multicultural, 1990-1996 (Box 54)
    - Multimodal, 1979-1992 (Box 54)
    - Multiversital, 1991-1994 (Box 54)
    - Musts, 1986-1996 (Box 114)
    - Narrative, 1989-1992 (Box 96)
    - Non-Verbal, 1972-1978 (Box 96)
    - Nuclear, 1959-1985 (Box 96)
    - Objections to RET, 1978-1984 (Box 114)
    - Obsession, 1983-1986 (Box 96)
    - Obesity, 1969-1971 (Box 96)
    - Objections, 1962-1995 (Box 96)
    - OCD, 1978-1993 (Box 96)
    - Pain, 1970-1996 (Box 96)
    - Panic, 1990-1992 (Box 96)
    - Paradox, 1974-1986 (Box 96)
    - Parenting, 1975-1985 (Box 96)
    - Peace/Anger, 2003 (Box 86)
    - Postmodern II, 1993-1998 (Box 86)
    - Postmodern III, 1997 (Box 86)
    - Philosophy, 2004 (Box 113)
    - Philosophy II, 1960-2004 (Box 54)
    - Rating II, III, 1991-2004, (7 folders) (Box 54)
    - RET Ideas, Undated (Box 86)
    - RET Emotions, 1982 (Box 86)
    - RET, 1969-1990 (Box 114)
    - RET Biography, 1966-2001 (Box 114)
    - RET Critique, Undated (Box 114)
    - RET and Ellis, 1971-2004 (Box 73)
    - Rationality Technique, 1963-1975 (Box 72)
    - Reason, 1963-1972 (Box 72)
    - Religion, 1958-1975, (6 folders) (Box 72)
    - Relaxation, 1982-1992 (Box 86)
    - Religion, 1980-2002, (4 folders) (Box 56)
    - Spiritual, 1990-2002, (2 folders) (Box 56)
    - Religion II, III, V, VII, VIII, 1966-2004, (10 folders) (Box 54)
    - Religion II, 1966-2005, (3 folders) (Box 95)
    - Self-Actualize, 1980-1996 (Box 114)
    - Sex--Myths, 1967-1972 (Box 107)
    - Sex, 1997-2003 (Box 113)
    - Stress, 1962-1979, (3 folders) (Box 106)
    - Tests, 1983-1984 (Box 86)
    - Transpersonal, 1983-2004, (5 folders) (Box 95)
    - Transpersonal Clairvoyance, 1969-2003 (Box 95)
    - Transpersonal Cult, 1973-2001, (2 folders) (Box 95)
    - Transpersonal Healing, 1996-2004, (2 folders) (Box 95)
    - Zen, 2002-2004 (Box 95)
    - To File, 2000-2005, (5 folders) (Box 95)
    - To File, 2004-2006, (11 folders) (Box 87)
    - To File, 1968-1974 (Box 114)
  - Notes
    - ACA Convention--Buttons, 1980-1995, Undated (Box 114)
    - Case Presents-Depression, 1980-1993, Undated (Box 114)
    - Diffs of RET-Hedonism, 1981-2000, Undated (Box 114)
    - Helpg People-Meaning of Life, 1976-2003, Undated (Box 114)
    - Miserable--Perf. Anx, 1986-1995, Undated (Box 114)
    - Pers. Discord--Rationality, 1985-1996, Undated (Box 114)
    - REBT-Relig, 1985-1996, Undated (Box 114)
    - Resistance--Sex Therapy, 1985-1996, Undated (Box 114)
    - Singles--Worrying, 1972-1995, Undated (Box 114)
    - Speeches, Undated (Box 72)
    - Comments by Ellis Regarding Others Speeches, Undated (Box 72)
    - Untitled, Undated (Box 114)
    - Untitled, Undated (Box 72)
    - Untitled--Photocopies, Undated (Box 72)
  - Transcripts (Box 57)
    - Patient Summaries
      - ONSBI, 1955-1957 (Box 57)
      - EOCDA, 1956 (Box 57)
      - ALASMA, 1956 (Box 57)
      - CEBDA, 1956-1958 (Box 57)
      - PAKEEL, 1957 (Box 57)
      - KARKMI, 1957 (Box 57)
      - NARJO, 1957 (Box 57)
      - GIEGSI, 1957 (Box 57)
      - SAAHL, 1957 (Box 57)
      - PAKFEL, 1957 (Box 57)
      - NUHSH, 1957 (Box 57)
      - ORBMY, 1957 (Box 57)
      - ORBSH, 1957 (Box 57)
      - DEERKE, 1957 (Box 57)
      - NAVIR, 1957 (Box 57)
      - NIEWWO, 1957 (Box 57)
      - EGNUFL, 1957 (Box 57)
      - SEOKGE, 1957 (Box 57)
      - SEWAL, 1957 (Box 57)
      - TIEDDA, 1957 (Box 57)
      - AWCMMI, 1957 (Box 57)
      - AWCMI, 1957 (Box 57)
      - NUHSH, 1957 (Box 57)
      - SEIWHO, 1957 (Box 57)
      - TOSGE, 1957 (Box 57)
      - NIEWEL, 1957 (Box 57)
      - CUZHE, 1957 (Box 57)
      - WORJA, 1957 (Box 57)
      - NEMCA, 1957 (Box 57)
      - NEJHA, 1957 (Box 57)
      - DORBGE, 1957 (Box 57)
      - ELPSU, 1957 (Box 57)
      - DORBEDA, 1957 (Box 57)
      - WORGRA, 1957 (Box 57)
      - MORLI, 1957 (Box 57)
      - SORBU, 1957 (Box 57)
      - DORBED, 1957 September 7, 14, 1958 May 3 (Box 91)
      - REDRO, 1957-1958 (Box 57)
      - RUFAN, 1957-1958 (Box 57)
      - SAYEI, 1957-1958 (Box 57)
      - KROSMU, 1957-1958 (Box 57)
      - PRUMMO, 1957-1958 (Box 57)
      - CEERBE, 1957-1958 (Box 57)
      - NHCSAL, 1957-1958 (Box 57)
      - AERBO, 1957-1958 (Box 57)
      - PAKFEL, 1957-1958 (Box 57)
      - SORBU, 1957-1958 (Box 57)
      - AERBBO, 1957-1958 (Box 57)
      - REDRO, 1958 (Box 57)
      - SORU, 1958 (Box 57)
      - SAAHAL, 1958 (Box 57)
      - DRODA, 1958 (Box 57)
      - HOCRU, 1958 (Box 57)
      - MATSDA, 1958 (Box 57)
      - ALGLE, 1958 (Box 57)
      - ZOKJE, 1958 (Box 57)
      - FAJHE, 1958 (Box 57)
      - BEWMOR, 1958 (Box 57)
      - SIEWSA, 1958 (Box 57)
      - SORGAL, 1958 (Box 57)
      - NIRGGA, 1958 (Box 57)
      - ARGNA, 1958 (Box 57)
      - FAJHE, 1958 (Box 57)
      - AERBDI, 1958 (Box 57)
      - LOPLO, 1958 (Box 57)
      - DOLBA, 1958 (Box 57)
      - ZOKJE, 1958 (Box 57)
      - ARGNA, 1958 March 3, April 24, May 1, 8, 22 (Box 91)
      - LAWTO, 1958 April 24, May 31, June 13 (Box 91)
      - DOLBA, 1958 April 1, Undated (Box 91)
      - LOPLO, 1958 May 14, 16, 23 (Box 91)
      - BEWMOR, 1958 May 26, June 12 (Box 91)
      - AERBDI, 1958 June 25, August 27, September 3 (Box 91)
      - IKDAFO/IKDAJO, 1958 March 9 (Box 91)
      - IHCSSU, 1957-1959 (Box 57)
      - ALGLE, 1957-1959 (Box 57)
      - DORBED, 1957-1959 (Box 57)
      - ERDHE, 1959 (Box 57)
      - EHCSLI, 1959 (Box 57)
      - BEWMOR, 1958-1959 (Box 57)
      - EHCAD, 1959 (Box 57)
      - VADDU, 1959 (Box 57)
      - EHGAD, 1959 (Box 57)
      - EHGAD/EHCAD, 1959 August 10 (Box 91)
      - IRTNA, 1959 December 15, 16, 1960 January 29, May 10 (Box 91)
      - ROMJO, 1960 January 13, October 3 (Box 91)
      - CIRLU, 1960 May 20, 27, July 22, 29 (Box 91)
      - ERFMO, 1960 July 21, August 25, 30, September 8 (Box 91)
      - LAWTO, 1958-1960 (Box 70)
      - IKDAJO, 1959-1960 (Box 70)
      - GIRLU, 1960 (Box 70)
      - IRTNA, 1960 (Box 70)
      - ROMJO, 1960 (Box 70)
      - ERFMO, 1960 (Box 70)
      - KROSMU, 1957-1961 (Box 70)
      - LYEST, 1961 (Box 70)
      - ROMRH, 1961 (Box 70)
      - LAHLA, 1961 (Box 70)
      - AELBE, 1962 (Box 70)
      - AELBE, 1962 December 3, 10, 17 (Box 91)
    - Transcripts (Box 70)
      - AEWCY, LIMLA, Undated (Box 70)
      - TEPJA, BENEV, RTSCA, AMALE, RIKSU, OTSLE, LIWDO, Undated (Box 70)
      - ORBDI, DOWKE, NISER, EHSTE, VESMA, SUKHE, Undated (Box 70)
      - ARGIS, ORGMI, GNELY, LIMDO, NAHJA, NEDLO, AHCFR, Undated (Box 70)
      - Gwen, Sexual Guilt, Undated (Box 70)
      - AOCCO--Hypnosis Tape, Need for Certainty, Undated (Box 70)
      - "A Translation of a Transcript of An Albert Ellis Therapy Session With a 31 Year Old Homosexual Client," 1965 (German) (Box 70)
      - LASFR (Box 91)
        - Conference Paper --"Presentation of a Young Male Homosexual Patient by Albert Ellis, Ph.D.," 1965 March 11, 12 (Box 91)
        - "Presentation of a Young Male Homosexual Patient by Albert Ellis, Ph.D, The Institute for Rational Living," Undated (Box 91)
        - Transcripts--Sessions Two, Three, Four, Five, 1964 August 28, September 12, 23, 30 (Box 91)
        - Transcripts--Sessions Six, Seven, Eight, 1964 October 7, 13, 22 (Box 91)
        - Transcripts--Sessions Nine, Ten, Eleven, 1964 October 28, November 3, 11 (Box 91)
      - American Academy of Psychotherapists (AAP) Tape Library (Box 70)
        - Volume 7--"Interview With Mike," by Carl Rogers, Undated (Box 70)
        - Volume 8--"Interview With P.S., A Seventeen Year Old Young Woman," by Carl Rogers, Undated (Box 70)
        - Volume 9--"27 Selections From a Psychotherapeutic Series With a Married Woman," Prepared by Abraham Levitsky, Undated (Box 70)
        - Volume 14--"Jim," by John Rosen, Undated (Box 70)
        - Volume 15--"Don," by Richard E. Felder and John Warkentin, Undated (Box 70)
        - Volume 16--"Gestalt Therapy Seminar," by Frederick Perls, Undated (Box 70)
        - Volume 18--"Gestalt Expressive Therapy," by Gene Sagan, 1960 (Box 70)
        - Volume 23--"Mr. and Mrs. Navnor," by Russell T. Baker, Undated (Box 70)
        - Volume 29--"Marnie," by Harold Greenwald, 1967 (Box 70)
        - Volume 30--"Desensitization for Phobia," Undated (Box 70)
        - Volume 31--"Individual Gestalt Therapy and An Interview with Dr. Frederick Perls," by James Simkin, Undated (Box 70)
        - Volume 32--"Self-Actualizing Group," by Ward A. Knight, 1966 (Box 70)
        - Volume 33--"The Case of Laura and the Therapeutic Self," by John G. Watkins, 1967 (Box 70)
        - Volume 34--"Rational Emotive Therapy: 4 Interviews," by Albert Ellis, Undated (Box 70)
        - Volume 37--"Directed Daydream Technique," by Max Hammer, Undated (Box 70)
        - Volume 38--"Behavioral Treatment of Stuttering," by John Paul Brady, 1968 (Box 70)
        - Volume 41--"Implosive Therapy," by Robert Hogan, Undated (Box 56)
        - Volume 86--"Dealing with Sexual Material," by Albert Ellis, Harold Greenwald, Virginia Satir, and Arthur Seagull, Undated (Box 56)
        - Volume 90--"Life Without Any Kind of Magic," by Albert Ellis, Undated (Box 56)
        - Felder and Warkentin with Male, Undated (Box 91)
        - Progoff with CR, Undated (Box 91)
        - Cameron with David (Chestnut Lodge), Undated (Box 91)
        - Rosen with Bill, Undated (Box 91)
        - Rollo May with Girl, Undated (Box 91)
        - Rollo May with Man, Undated (Box 91)
        - Albert Ellis with EITTO, Undated (Box 91)
      - Donald Webster Cory Interview with Albert Ellis, Undated (Box 56)
      - Session with Ellis, 1970 (Box 56)
      - Ellis Session with Children, 1970 (Box 56)
      - Interview with Albert Ellis, 1984 (Box 56)
      - Transcript of D.C. Meeting, 1985 (Box 56)
      - Interview with Dr. Albert Ellis, 1991 March 13 (Box 56)
      - "Interview with a Young Male Homosexual Treated with Rational-Emotive Psychotherapy," Undated (Box 56)
      - "Married Male Who was Compulsively Addicted to Homosexuality," Undated (Box 56)
  - Non-Ellis (Box 72)
    - The Anger Control Workbook, by Matthew McKay, Ph.D., and Peter D. Rogers, Ph.D., New Harbinger Publications, 2000 (Box 72)
    - Anger Management: The Complete Guidebook for Practitioners, by Kassinove and Tafrate, 2002 (Box 76)
    - Brief Therapy with Individuals and Couples, Edited by Jon Carlson and Len Sperry, Zeig, Tucker, and Theisen, Inc., Publishers, 2000 (Box 72)